[GREGSON]
Hey! Watch him! He's running!
[HOLMES]
Quiet, Gregson!
Give me some warning next time.
Did you find another clue?
Perhaps.
[HOLMES]
How curious.
[HOLMES] Lestrade, listen.
To solve this...
I need to escape.
[LESTRADE gasps]
[HOLMES]
Hmm.
[GREGSON] The best consulting
detective, indeed!
Hah. We're getting a menace
off the streets for good.
To solve this...
I need to escape.
I can't find the true
culprit behind bars.
When this mystery's concluded,
you and the Yard can
take credit for solving it.
But first, I'm going to need
you to do me this favour.
[LESTRADE]
The true culprit, huh?
You'd better make sure
you do catch them.
Ugh, fine.
[GREGSON yelps]
[GREGSON groans]
- -[POLICE 8A] Get him!
- -[POLICE 8B] Oi!
[gasps] Come back here!
Inspector!
Don't blame me!
Something startled the horse!
[HOLMES]
Sorry to keep you waiting.
[WATSON]
Sherlock!
I'm relieved you managed
to slip away from them.
[WATSON]
The inspector took the risk.
Exactly as you
said in your note.
Smart chap. Although,
I'm a wanted man with
Scotland Yard hunting me.
So, John.
Do you still want to get
involved in this case?
Yes, of course.
After all, if you go to prison,
who do you think's
going to end up
having to pay
your half of the rent?
To avoid such a heinous crime,
we must settle this quickly.
[WATSON grunts]
Wait.
Do you already know
who the culprit is?
As to their
specific identity, no.
Not yet.
But after laying a trap
with this, we'll lure them in.
Someone's ring.
[WATSON gasps]
[WATSON]
You found it by the desk?
What can I say? I have a rare
talent for pilfering things.
[WATSON]
Mm. Do me a favor.
Going forward,
will you only use these
abilities for the greater good?
[FRED] So, you left
your ring at the scene.
[HOPE]
I'm sorry.
Listen. I need to get it back,
whatever it takes.
It's more precious to me
than my life! [groans]
I'll do my best.
"I found a golden ring
in Three, Lauriston Gardens
off the Brixton Road.
If you might be the owner,
contact Doctor John H. Watson.
Two, two, one, B,
Baker Street?"
Well?
He's setting a trap for us.
Are you sure we
should send Fred then?
[WILLIAM] Improvisation
is part of theatre.
And not to mention, there's
Hope's final wish to consider.
No harm in granting it.
[HOLMES]
Good. The carrot is dangled.
Now that's done,
what's our next step?
So glad you asked.
[WIGGINS]
Ready. I've rounded 'em all up.
And you are?
I am the captain of the infamous
Baker Street Irregulars.
Name's Wiggins.
They don't work for you, right?
They're only children.
To the untrained eye,
a band of grimy street urchins.
You didn't have to
call us grimy, guv.
[HOLMES]
They do everything,
from finding lost goods
to running errands.
After all, the whole
city is their home.
They're far more
helpful than the police.
[WIGGINS grunts]
[HOLMES]
Consider them my eyes and ears.
[WIGGINS]
Hm?
We ain't your minions, you know!
And don't expect us to
work for free none either!
Please, you know me.
You will receive your reward,
after you finish the job.
I'm confused. What exactly
are these lads going to do?
Just provide a
little assistance.
[WATSON]
Lucy, hmm?
So it's a women's wedding band.
And judging by the design,
not an aristocratic union.
By Sherlock's deduction,
the culprit dropped this
at the crime scene.
Basically, it's
our only evidence.
If it belongs to the killer,
they're certain to
come looking for it.
[HOLMES] It would be
the most logical answer.
The real killer was much
larger in stature than Drebber.
[WATSON]
In person he must be a giant.
[WATSON grunts]
[knocking]
[WATSON gasps]
[WATSON]
Yes? How may I... help... you?
[OLD WOMAN] I'm here
regarding the missing ring
you posted about
in the newspaper.
Thank you for the advert.
Otherwise, my Lucy might
have lost it for good.
[WATSON]
An old woman?
[OLD WOMAN]
My daughter's name should be
inscribed on the inside
of the ring, yes?
[WATSON]
Uh, it is.
[OLD WOMAN]
She believes she dropped it
somewhere near Number Three.
She only just got married
last year. It's tragic.
If her husband finds out
she lost her precious ring,
he would be terribly
angry with her.
[WATSON grunts]
Well, we can't have that.
Here you are.
[gasps]
Spry for a little old lady!
[HOLMES]
Hmm.
- -[OLD WOMAN gasps]
- -[HOLMES grunts]
[HOLMES yells]
[FRED groans]
Now, to find out
who you really are--
[HOLMES gasps, shouts]
You there, stop!
Damn! I should've
known they wouldn't
let themselves get
caught so easily.
They got one over on me.
[WATSON]
That man just now,
was he the mastermind
we're searching for?
[HOLMES] No. Probably just
one of his associates.
[WATSON] Meaning there
are more. In that case,
you believe they're some
sort of organization?
More than likely, yes.
But that'll have
to wait for the moment
as finding Drebber's
killer comes first.
But how?
That ring was the only lead
we had and now it's gone.
What? No need to be so gloomy.
At this point, John,
the crime is all but solved.
[gasps]
Are you telling me you know
who murdered Lord Drebber?
Sure.
Well then, who on
earth is the killer?
[HOLMES]
Perfect.
Why don't you wait
for me in there?
I shan't be long.
But, Sherlock.
Wait! Where're you...?
[WATSON]
Unbelievable.
Did he really discover
who the killer is?
Why'd he have to
keep me in suspense?
[WATSON]
Hm?
All done. Let's go.
[HOLMES]
This arrived from Lestrade.
Take a look.
[HOLMES]
Lord Drebber's past.
I asked the inspector
to check into it for me.
The man was a
philanderer without equal.
With a particular fondness for
molesting women
of lower standing.
We can't begin to imagine
what they were forced to endure.
If a victim threatened to talk,
he usually settled
the matter with money.
Unfortunately,
there was one who proved to be
an exception to this rule.
Lucy Ferrier.
She had recently
married a local farmer
by the name of Jefferson Hope.
When her body was discovered,
her remains were returned home.
Sadly, there were
a significant number
of horrifying
bruises to the body.
[WATSON grunts] This is a
positively tragic story.
You're saying,
the true killer is--
[HOLMES] The man who
took Lord Drebber's life,
is the same Jefferson
Hope, murderer...
...and our driver, oddly enough.
[gasps]
Isn't that right,
Jefferson Hope?
I must say, I'm surprised you
investigated so thoroughly.
You know, having
your carriage driven
by a murderer isn't something
many people get to experience.
Look, I'm not doubting
your methods, Holmes,
but even if the
inscription on the ring
is connected to
this Jefferson Hope,
that's still not
enough evidence to prove
that he's the same man
as our cab driver!
You raise a good point.
I arrived at my conclusion from
two different lines
of reasoning.
The first one was
the ring that we found.
The second was a set
of wheel tracks.
Thanks to some rain earlier
that evening at the scene,
they were quite visible.
All the houses
belonged to noblemen,
who own four-wheeled carriages,
driven by two-horses.
However, in front of
the Earl's manor,
there were smaller tracks
belonging to a narrower cab.
No killer would
be foolish enough
to arrive in a carriage,
commit the murder,
hop back in the cab,
then return home.
Otherwise,
the driver would have had
a clear view of
whoever the killer was.
Which means...
...the culprit was someone who
bore no risk of that happening.
What remains?
He would have had to
drive himself there.
In response,
I sent the Irregulars off
in search of someone who
met the following criteria:
A driver of a hansom cab,
who was a large man
with pudgy fingers.
Additionally, they would have
gone to Number Three
the day of the crime.
One person came up right away.
[WATSON]
Let me guess, Jefferson Hope.
Despite not knowing the
contents of Lestrade's report,
the Irregulars
turned up the same man.
[HOLMES]
In short,
It wasn't difficult to
put a name to the shooter.
Case closed.
One question.
The manner in which
you killed Drebber--
why so coarse?
The plan demanded
precision on all levels.
Elegance, yet your
execution was sloppy.
[HOPE]
It's true.
Though his death was to be
carried out with more finesse,
I couldn't help myself!
Not when I came
face to face with Drebber.
You expected me to
remain level-headed?
Seeing that monster?
The man who killed my wife?
[HOPE]
Well, Sherlock Holmes...
...how about making
a deal with me?
Be smart, Mister Hope.
You've already achieved
your goal, haven't you?
Is that not enough?
Turn yourself into the police.
Turn myself in?
[groans]
[HOPE coughs]
A futile gesture. You see,
I don't have much time left.
At this stage of the game,
I may as well be dead.
All's lost. I gave all
I had to my benefactor.
This deal--and what,
pray tell, are the terms?
It's a simple matter, gentlemen.
[WATSON gasps]
[HOPE]
My life has been destroyed
by the corruption
of aristocrats.
My tale's at an end, and
I want you to close the book.
In other words, pick up the
gun and end this suffering.
[grunts]
[HOPE] Since you uncovered
Drebber's vile sins,
it's only fitting
that I die by your hand.
[HOLMES]
Hm?
And who's that?
[HOPE] The one who got
Lucy's ring back for me.
[HOPE] Events have
been carefully arranged
after I'm dead.
Kill me and he'll reveal the
identity of my benefactor.
[HOLMES]
Tending to your affairs before
you're even gone from this
world. How very thorough.
Yes, indeed.
He truly is an incredible
person.
[HOPE] When I arrived
at Drebber's mansion
at the appointed time,
the door opened as if by magic,
and there was nary a soul
around to interfere.
The man is a true
criminal genius.
My benefactor holds
you in high regard.
Enough to want your name
left at the scene to see
if you could solve the case.
But to what end, though?
Why engineer such
an elaborate scheme?
[HOPE]
You wanna know?
Pull the trigger and
all will be revealed.
Tempting,
but seeing how I'm considered
a murder suspect on the run,
I don't think killing you
would do much in the
way of clearing my name.
Don't worry about that.
Once you shoot me, he'll arrange
for a witness to come forward,
providing testimony that'll all
but guarantee your freedom.
You see? The arrangement
benefits you as well.
Kill me and both of us
will get exactly what we desire.
Make your decision, sir.
[HOLMES]
You're right.
It would prove a great
relief to the both of us.
I can't let you do that!
You know that this is wrong!
[HOLMES]
How so?
He gets a quick death
and I get the identity
of the mastermind.
That may be true.
But shoot that gun,
and there's no going back!
[HOPE]
Don't listen to him!
You're a man who
seeks out mysteries.
There's no satisfaction
without a solution.
And you want to know who
created the ultimate
mystery, don't you?
So, shoot me and
you'll have your answer!
[HOLMES grunts]
No, Sherlock, please!
Put it down!
Don't do it!
[gun fires]
[HOPE grunts]
[gasps]
[HOLMES laughing]
So sorry. I won't kill you.
[HOPE] You're a fool if you
don't!
Their identity will stay a
secret!
[HOLMES] I'll have to figure it
out on my own?
Huh. Now imagine that.
Please, enough insults,
you daft bastard.
See here!
The satisfaction is finding
the solution on your own!
There's always some sod
that comes along and
tries spoiling my fun!
I'll have none of it!
[WATSON]
Oh, thank God.
Seriously, thank God.
- -[HOLMES] John?
- -[WATSON] I'm so sorry!
[HOLMES]
Just pull yourself together!
[WATSON] Please forgive me
for doubting you!
Even for a moment!
[HOLMES] You're forgiven.
Just get off of me!
[HOLMES]
Truly,
I'm sorry I wasn't able
to grant your request.
Your final wish.
[HOPE gasps]
[inhales]
Ah, Scotland Yard!
Have you bungled
any cases, lately?
I'd like you to meet someone.
Allow me to present the actual
killer of Lord Enoch J. Drebber,
Jefferson Hope!
Sherlock Holmes?! Why is...?!
You caught him!
I kept my end of
the bargain as promised.
[WILLIAM] Consulting
detective, Sherlock Holmes.
[WILLIAM]
Somehow, he managed to slip away
from Scotland Yard
and solve the case.
Thoughts?
Very impressive the way
he discerned the murder
was planned by
a separate individual.
I would say his
competency as a detective
appears to be quite genuine.
The audition provided us
with all the answers
we had hoped it would.
We knew what sort
of mind he had,
but nothing of his heart.
My goal
was to see whether
he'd resort to any means
in order to achieve his,
and he won't.
Even after we offered him
all the answers on
a silver platter, no dice.
He still didn't go
for Hope's proposal.
[LOUIS]
According to William's analysis,
Holmes has a keen interest
in finding the mastermind.
The one pulling the
strings from the dark.
And yet he refused to kill Hope.
When it comes to
accomplishing his goals,
he has limits, making
him different from us.
Then he's worthy, right,
this man, Holmes?
From here on out,
there will be a new character
in this crime drama
we've been staging.
A detective striving
to solve the case.
[WILLIAM] I believe
we have found our leading man.
A beacon in a dark world.
[WILLIAM]
Sherlock Holmes.
[WATSON]
Is it morning already?
I think I'll go downstairs
and make some tea.
[HOLMES snoring]
[WATSON] As long as
I'm living here with you,
I'll never be in want
of writing material.
I'm sure of it.
[WILLIAM] Next time
on Moriarty the Patriot  .
"The Two Detectives. Act One."